<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-04-05T02:27:03+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//</id><title type="html">Stuff Full of Stuff</title><subtitle>Portfolio and writings of an eccentric illustrator and painter</subtitle><author><name>ACE</name></author><entry><title type="html">Illustration: Soul Matter - Pelican</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/illustration/soul-matter-pelican-album-cover-art/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Illustration: Soul Matter - Pelican" /><published>2017-04-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-04-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/illustration/soul-matter-pelican-album-cover-art</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/illustration/soul-matter-pelican-album-cover-art/">&lt;figure class=&quot; &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gallery/soul-matter-colour.png&quot; title=&quot;Soul Matter Album Art&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gallery/soul-matter-colour.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The cover art for the Soul Matter 2017 album.
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past month, I’ve been trying to get some freelance work as an illustrator. Most of the requests I’ve gotten (which weren’t many, since I’m currently only using Craigslist, but hope to further my endeavours after the end of my other freelance project) were for logo design, even though I advertise illustrations. In any case, I have gotten some work … not much, but the best deal I’ve gotten was to do an album art cover for Soul Matter second album, music by an independent artist, Trevor Hougardy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent a few weeks working on this piece. Since I have seen and been working on it for a while, I’m not impressed by it; a feeling that is not uncommon with anyone who has a creative bent. I also would have preferred not to have lineart with a painted look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept behind this was a grand appearance, dynamic feel of flying in the air, in order to match with the music. A pelican is flying into the canyons, out from the forest. There’s also water near the canyons. Pelican’s and canyons don’t mix, but with water they do. It’s unusual idea, but I think it worked very well. This piece is a little conventional, but the pelican adds to an abstract expression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally the work was optimized to be black and white, though the request was to paint it in colour with an inkling of 70s faded colours, similar to folk colours. A couple of problems with the creation of the work: black lineart on clouds with painted look doesn’t necessarily look good because it decreases the fluffy tenderness of cloud’s inherent nature. The clouds have to be tender, so the lineart was coloured various shades. A second problem, that I feel always plagues black lineart mixed with paint, is the black lineart lends to a ‘grittier’ look to a picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also recreated the title in Illustrator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot; &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/SOUL_MATTER_FONT_1000.png&quot; title=&quot;Soul Matter Album Art Logo&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/SOUL_MATTER_FONT_1000.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The created logo for the Soul Matter 2017 album.
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I feel this was a good step towards more commercial work. I hope it provides a little bit of exposure. In the meanwhile, a lot of work, as always, is to be done to improve my skill.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ACE</name></author><category term="work in progress" /><category term="written image" /><category term="sketches" /><category term="composition" /><category term="being a freelance artist" /><category term="commercial art" /><summary type="html">The cover art for the Soul Matter 2017 album.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Work in Progress: Empty Parking Lot</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/written%20image/part-1-empty-parking-lot/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Work in Progress: Empty Parking Lot" /><published>2017-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/written%20image/part-1-empty-parking-lot</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/written%20image/part-1-empty-parking-lot/">&lt;p&gt;This is a work in progress for the written image titled “Empty Parking Lot”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full written image of Empty Parking Lot can be read &lt;a href=&quot;/text/empty/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is half of the image that is part of Empty Parking Lot. I actually lost the second sketch, which would detail the empty parking lot, so I have to redraw it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an actual dream I had, where it started at the bookstore and at one point, at a time of 4 AM (in the dream), there was an empty parking lot. I won’t go into detail of this dream, but it was another story dream I tend to have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attempted to accurately draw the entrance to the bookstore from my dream, but it’s not 100% what it looked like. Plus, the dream was in colour … the bookstore was a hazy red colour, while the outside was that warm yellow glow you would find in cozy towns on a night out (though, I’ve never been on a ‘night out’). And what else is missing are the two people, but leaving the composition barren of humanity makes the picture give an aura of emptiness. I still think about adding the person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mulled over whether the picture was going to be B&amp;amp;W or colour, but I decided on keeping my written images consistent: B&amp;amp;W it is!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Been drawing too many B&amp;amp;Ws but a colour image is in the works.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ACE</name></author><category term="work in progress" /><category term="written image" /><category term="sketches" /><category term="composition" /><summary type="html">This is a work in progress for the written image titled “Empty Parking Lot”.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Painting: Variance Number 6</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/painting/variance-no-6/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Painting: Variance Number 6" /><published>2017-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/painting/variance-no-6</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/painting/variance-no-6/">&lt;p&gt;I set this variance as the header for the splash page of my portfolio. This is a bold and bizarre piece that I had sketched out back in August. But it was only in January this year that I completed it, thanks to time permitting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot; &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gallery/radface3.png&quot; title=&quot;Variance Number 6&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gallery/radface3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common theme I like to draw are the twins, Sigmana and Phirem. I like to draw them because I can make them look disheveled, bizarre, unconventional. I’m tired of seeing artists draw characters that look like picture perfect models, and from the other side of the spectrum, uninteresting “shapes”. One of my influences for making the delicate creatures is Nagano Mamoru illustrations of his characters. Particularly, his Fatima’s look haunting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I tried to pick print safe colours, but, because I had this image on the backburner for months, I didn’t care when I picked it up again a few weeks ago. Nevertheless, I kept the palette at a minimum and chose vibrant, almost jarring colours. When I do a variance painting, I like to choose colours that may not work next to each other. Sometimes colours we think are disharmonious together, can be used to support or emphasize on another colour. I played it safe with this piece, though. Sigmana’s dull blue hair is a great contrast to the hot pink background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is another large image (6500 x 3300). A larger view is accessible through the gallery, in the portfolio section.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ACE</name></author><category term="variance" /><category term="written image" /><category term="sigmana" /><category term="phirem" /><category term="sketches" /><category term="composition" /><category term="painting" /><summary type="html">I set this variance as the header for the splash page of my portfolio. This is a bold and bizarre piece that I had sketched out back in August. But it was only in January this year that I completed it, thanks to time permitting.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Painting: Twins</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/painting/twins/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Painting: Twins" /><published>2017-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/painting/twins</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/painting/twins/">&lt;p&gt;Again, this is Sigmana and Phirem (the twins). I’ve drawn them a lot, but the next pictures planned have nothing to do with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot; &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gallery/thetwins3.png&quot; title=&quot;Twins&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gallery/thetwins3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked on this throughout December, and finished it in the beginning of January. It wasn’t a difficult piece; originally I was going to make it lineart, but after seeing how my painting looked without the lines, I decided to make it look realistic. I particularly like how Sigmana’s face turned out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since they are both artificially created, they aren’t supposed to look organic, though Phirem has quite an expressive personality. Sigmana is the prototype, or the ‘not as good as it could be’ type, so it’s going to look expressionless (Sigmana is well aware of its existence, however).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their skin colour is a sickly blue, with some signs of ‘life’ around their eyes (pink).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;phirem&quot;&gt;Phirem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I struggled a lot with making Phirem’s face. I looked at references of mischevous children and fortunately, that helped. Still, to get a certain emotion out of its face was a challenge, and I am pleased with the result. Here are some sketches of what the twins looked like before. When I have difficulty, I will sketch many, many times until I get it right, or I do a study in which I practice a reference. This way, I am learning how to apply it to my own piece, as well as learning how to draw [a certain thing].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;third &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/feb2017/floating.png&quot; title=&quot;Floating head&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/feb2017/floating.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/feb2017/sketch_t.png&quot; title=&quot;Original sketches (sort of)&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/feb2017/sketch_t.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/feb2017/sketch_t2.png&quot; title=&quot;Pretty bad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/feb2017/sketch_t2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>ACE</name></author><category term="sigmana" /><category term="phirem" /><category term="process" /><category term="sketches" /><category term="lineart" /><category term="composition" /><summary type="html">Again, this is Sigmana and Phirem (the twins). I’ve drawn them a lot, but the next pictures planned have nothing to do with them.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Written Image: Content</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/written%20image/content/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Written Image: Content" /><published>2016-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/written%20image/content</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/written%20image/content/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;this piece is enourmous: &lt;strong&gt;4748 x 3500&lt;/strong&gt;. best viewed in full screen; please view it in the gallery as well!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stuffostuff.com/assets/images/gallery/sunflowerfall.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stuffostuff.com/assets/images/gallery/sunflowerfall.png&quot; alt=&quot;foo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;setting-the-tone&quot;&gt;Setting the tone&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a very simple piece. Another written image, similar to the Jellyfish. One can say it’s the grownup version of the standard child’s drawing of a hill, house, sun, tree and stick figure, due to the horizontal composition. Much of the inspiration came from a dedicated video of Tuxedomoon’s piece “Lowlands Tone Poem”, and a house I would walk by as I went to the grocery store. The house looked standard of the area where my university is located; shabby, but it had a unique charm to it: many sunflowers right out front. I thought, ‘this house is not American’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;his-emotions&quot;&gt;His emotions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His appearance here amongst the minimal setting fleshes his personality completely. He isn’t depressed, and he isn’t a sad fellow. He isn’t happy either. He just is what he is. I think that’s the best way to live life, not to have so many ups and downs. Going through life as an active observer and aware of your environment, you tend to be content, forgiving of other people, and generally an easy going person. These types of individuals are not wishy-washy; they aren’t ecstatic, nor wild or morose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;background-on-the-creation&quot;&gt;Background on the creation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the creation of the image: the image is huge - 4748 x 3500 pixels. Not a good idea to draw this large with black and white work. It took a very long time and at some points, the work was exceedingly tedious and painful. Drawing each individual sunflower was a pretty bad experience. I spent a few weeks mulling over how I would plan out the sunflowers and I had difficulty drawing them at first (after some practice, I figured out my way of drawing these bright flowers). I was frustrated, and kept flip flopping between not including the flowers in the picture. I wagered the picture simply is not the same without the sunflowers – after all, it is my primary inspiration for the piece. After the initial line work was complete, the drawing went smoothly. To make the effect of the body of the sunflower, I simply laid over a noise layer. There’s no way I’d do each individual dot for each sunflower. Pure masochism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was going to be a street lamp, but maybe it would crowd the picture. On a second thought, perhaps I should have added it. There’s also no blue shed either, though I imagine he’s coming close to it. The priority was on the sunflowers and sky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, I too walk with an umbrella and briefcase.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ACE</name></author><category term="black and white ink" /><category term="written image" /><category term="fantasy man" /><category term="process" /><category term="sketches" /><category term="lineart" /><category term="composition" /><category term="sunflower black and white" /><category term="noise" /><summary type="html">this piece is enourmous: 4748 x 3500. best viewed in full screen; please view it in the gallery as well!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Written Image: Jellyfish</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/written%20image/jellyfish/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Written Image: Jellyfish" /><published>2016-09-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-09-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/written%20image/jellyfish</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/written%20image/jellyfish/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-jellyfish&quot;&gt;2 Jellyfish&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gallery/jellyfish_duplicate_3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-rest&quot;&gt;The rest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I wrote about jellyfish. I’m not going to say this is a poem – I won’t claim I can write poetry. Instead, I wrote an image on jellyfish. Images are different from poems … I think my goal was to create something that moves, rather than crafting with words. By this word ‘written image’, I mean the qualitative characteristics of what an image, which is a visual representation of a thing, provides. Think of the term ‘written image’ as something more technical and abstract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-a-written-image-in-my-terms&quot;&gt;What is a written image (in my terms)?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, words weren’t enough, so I decided to take writing an image literally: drawing an image (now, I use the term ‘image’ with the basic connotation: visual representation). That’s what makes a written image complete. A poem can have an image attached, but was the poem originally intended to have an image? If it wasn’t intended to have an image then it’s certainly a poem. If an image was in mind and then included, then there is a written image. Take note that the words are also a part of the drawing. It’s not in a random space on the page, but blending with the jellyfish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is what a written image is, summed up in a basic manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an addition to this post, my portfolio would not be complete without the actual drawing. Here’s the jellyfish without the written image. I am pleased with the line work. I drew the jellyfish in a quick manner; about two hours total. I kept the shading and bw work at a minimum because that would obscure the very delicate line work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/september/jellyfish_lineart.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ACE</name></author><category term="black and white ink" /><category term="written image poetry" /><category term="jellyfish black and white" /><category term="process" /><category term="sketches" /><category term="lineart" /><category term="composition" /><summary type="html">2 Jellyfish</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Painting: Variance Number 5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/painting/variance-no-5/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Painting: Variance Number 5" /><published>2016-09-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-09-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/painting/variance-no-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/painting/variance-no-5/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gallery/wolfe1_copy_3_lineart_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each time I look at this picture I get the sense of – dryness –. Certain amount of ugliness. There’s enough vibrancy to ensure this picture will gather the attention of those that enjoy neon colour schemes, but it is subdued by the dull background – pale mauve, gray periwinkle and a midnight blue: light enough to share the same space with the mauve and periwinkle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is also my first definite picture to incorporate only CMYK values. They were selected from the Pantone +CMYK library. It worked pretty well. This was the palette I worked with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/september/palette.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only colour I didn’t use was the light green. 
I proofed the image, and only the green in the man’s cloak dulls a tad; the green was mixed too much with the blue while painting, so the green, which is greenish-blue, does not properly come out when switched to CMYK. The rest of the colours keep consistent.
The initial concept came from a sketch I drew in an old sketch book of mine, back in 2014. I probably sketched it in one of my art classes and I was going to eventually plan it out as an image but I never did. The character is Wolfe, a shape shifter. Two years later, and here is a much nicer rendition of the original. I do not have this sketch book with me currently so no scan of the original is available. 
A black and white creation of the image might be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/wolfe1_lineart.png&quot; caption=&quot;Wolfe lineart&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ACE</name></author><category term="painting" /><category term="variance" /><category term="fantasy man" /><category term="process" /><category term="sketches" /><category term="lineart" /><category term="composition" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Illustration: Brom</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/illustration/brom/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Illustration: Brom" /><published>2016-08-14T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-08-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/illustration/brom</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/illustration/brom/">&lt;p&gt;I’m trying to come up with a comfortable, conventional colouring style that involves some sort of line art. I’ve spent too much time with black and white so I am lacking. With this piece, I decided to use my Variance style, twisting it to make it less abstract. More importantly, this is a concept character design (that I redid three times) and was great colouring practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;space-detective-brom&quot;&gt;Space Detective Brom&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gallery/brom2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is Brom, a concept art of a character. He’s a space detective and has a cyborg eye. Well I didn’t want the eye to look so mechanical and average. So it’s simply blue, though his eye changes colours depending on what wavelength he needs to hone in on. Blue is for visible light. He looks pretty regular as far as detectives go, besides his hair. I realized too late that his hair bears a little resemblance to Professor Oak… Ahh, well I did want Brom to have a ‘cyberpunk’ hair style. Sleek hair is popular in fashion today, but not popular with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overlay-manipulation&quot;&gt;Overlay manipulation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another good practice was overlay manipulation to get some above standard effects. It was boring with just the colouring. I like the texture I gave to the coat, as well as some dirt to the shoes.
There were a lot of revisions with this picture. Check them out here (this was the cause for the unbelievable long time it took to finish his design):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/brom_1.png&quot; title=&quot;A different version of Brom&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/brom_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;different version&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/brom_2.png&quot; title=&quot;Brom sketch&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/brom_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;brom sketch&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>ACE</name></author><category term="design process" /><category term="illustration" /><category term="space detective" /><category term="cyber-punk" /><category term="lineart" /><category term="process" /><category term="composition" /><category term="concept" /><summary type="html">I’m trying to come up with a comfortable, conventional colouring style that involves some sort of line art. I’ve spent too much time with black and white so I am lacking. With this piece, I decided to use my Variance style, twisting it to make it less abstract. More importantly, this is a concept character design (that I redid three times) and was great colouring practice.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Illustration: 2.5 x 10^6 ly</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/illustration/andromeda-galaxy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Illustration: 2.5 x 10^6 ly" /><published>2016-07-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-07-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/illustration/andromeda-galaxy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/illustration/andromeda-galaxy/">&lt;p&gt;The value is associated with astronomy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gallery/redandiota.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gallery/redandiota_flipped.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is another black and white image. It seems like I am trying to avoid colour images. Well, not with the last… (Variance Number 4).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, the good thing that I’ve noticed is that I am doing these black and white images a lot quicker. The linework still takes time, but the actual blacking in is taking less and less each picture. This one was an easy one though I had worked on it for several weeks, on and off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favourite part of the image? The galaxy in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Red and Iota, the leaders of the Rebel group, until Red (the guy with the long hair) goes on a mission somewhere else. Iota on the other hand, is not as charismatic, hardly, making for a bad leader. He is austere, deep in thought and generally not a great Andromedian to chat with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this picture I wanted to incorporate more design. Originally it wasn’t going to have the black borders nor the value, however I was itching to make more out of this piece. It looked boring without the value and borders. This now closes it and makes it polished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the original sketch. I had forgotten the galaxy was going to be titled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/risketch.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ACE</name></author><category term="black and white" /><category term="design process" /><category term="illustration" /><category term="space opera" /><category term="iota" /><category term="red" /><category term="lineart" /><category term="how to draw black and white" /><category term="process" /><category term="composition" /><summary type="html">The value is associated with astronomy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Painting: Variance Number 4</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/painting/variance-no-4/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Painting: Variance Number 4" /><published>2016-07-14T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-07-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/painting/variance-no-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/painting/variance-no-4/">&lt;p&gt;Here’s variance number 4. I suppose I skipped number 3 too soon.
The International Accounting Concept midterm exam was due today. So I am turning this in as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/sigmanathumbnail.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not here not there, not where.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sigmana is the feature. This stemmed from a montage of sketches I wanted to do of Sigmana and Phirem. This one was a sketch I wanted to completely develop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/sigmanasketch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I retained the sketchy background, though reducing the opacity to 39%. It gives it a good edge, messy, gritty, rich. It’s too smooth without it. And I like the way the orange clashes with the red, though the red mixes with the weak blue carefully. The weak blue is on a different saturation level from the red, but the red pops within the confines of the blues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original size of the image is huge: &lt;strong&gt;4000 x 4800&lt;/strong&gt;. But here it’s down to 11% of its original size. Additionally a few adjustments to the originals curves allowing the light to be equal amongst the darks was done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there’s that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ACE</name></author><category term="composition" /><category term="illustration" /><category term="sigmana" /><category term="space opera" /><category term="variance" /><category term="color design" /><category term="sketches" /><summary type="html">Here’s variance number 4. I suppose I skipped number 3 too soon.
The International Accounting Concept midterm exam was due today. So I am turning this in as well.</summary></entry></feed>
