<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-01-12T03:07:06+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//</id><title type="html">Stuff Full of Stuff</title><subtitle>Portfolio and writings of an eccentric illustrator and painter</subtitle><author><name>ACE</name><email>aceiotasirrah@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Tarot reading done by me back in October</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tarot%20reading%20example/writings/spirituality/love%20and%20romance/tarot/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tarot reading done by me back in October" /><published>2017-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tarot%20reading%20example/writings/spirituality/love%20and%20romance/tarot</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tarot%20reading%20example/writings/spirituality/love%20and%20romance/tarot/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This was a tarot reading I wrote for a customer back in October 9. It also contains valuable insights into the tarot and spirituality as a whole.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-reading&quot;&gt;The reading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kelly, I am very excited to delve deep into your love reading. You shared a good, brief description and a wonderful question. That helps a reader a lot because it enables me to jangle the Tarot into giving me deeper knowledge about the relationship you have with the man you love. 
Your question was,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Was Carl and I soul mates in a past life, or will there be something for us in our future?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to reword it and add more substance for the Tarot; cushion it a little bit, because the Tarot likes specifics.
“Tarot, please give me insight as to whether Carl and Kelly were soul mates in a past life, or at least, is there the possibility of a relationship between the two, in the future?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cards were drawn in a basic but powerful spread: &lt;em&gt;past&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;present&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;future&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;third &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/past.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Past: 9 of Wands&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/past.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;past&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/present.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Present: The Empress&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/present.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;present&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/wof.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Future: Wheel of Fortune&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/wof.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;future&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;BACKGROUND&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Past: 9 of Wands&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Minor Arcana&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The card of perseverance. Sometimes I view this card as earthy, like a Pentacle, because of the amazing strength the man has. After being beaten down until he’s wrapped in bandages, he continues the path he is on ever vigilantly. The eight other wands serve as a barrier for his psyche and body. He uses it to fence himself in, so he’ll avoid getting hurt one more time. That doesn’t mean he’s giving up, though. It’s wise for him to do this, because people can only take so much of distraught caused by various situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man needs to be careful not to block everything from entering his sphere. This is harmful in relation to new relationships, for example. For example, some people who have been deeply scarred by past relationships usually guard themselves from a new prospect of love; this only worsens any future relationships the person can have. The man should keep his stamina, and as long as he is wise in his watchful nature, he will be able to discern who is giving a hand, or is trying to stir another would to his heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This card has a different meaning for you, however. The meaning is fully discussed in the “RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN ALL THREE” section of this analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Present: The Empress&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Major Arcana&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Number three of the Major Arcana, The Empress is the ultimate card signifying the feminine nature of everything. The card even has the symbol of female etched onto a rock. That etching is commonly associated with Venus, the feminine character of humanity; the lover, the embodiment of the Western Female. The Empress proudly sits on a luxurious chair that is very comfortable. As you can see, there are pillows and blankets which cover the hard stone the chair is sitting on top of. She lives in comfort and as a person, makes the home; the mother figure. She makes everything comfortable for her residents and people outside of her sphere. Notice the wheat at the bottom of her feet. Water is flowing from the distance, into the wheat to keep it growing. Wheat signifies harvest, and in Paganism, the harvest time as always been associated with fertility. This fertility reinforces the motherly figure this card exudes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of love, and in the present condition, the Empress is a good card to see. It says you are carrying a huge amount of love within yourself for someone else, but you don’t just want to keep it. The Empress doesn’t keep; if she did, why would she have a bountiful harvest beneath her feet? That is food to give to others. Your bountiful love you harbor inside is just aching to be transferred to someone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Future: Wheel of Fortune&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Major Arcana&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has always been an oddball of a card! It is one of the most ambiguous Major Arcana. But to sum up, it’s the card of destiny! Destiny or fate, is much like a wheel of fortune, wouldn’t you think? That is, if you believe in fate being entirely up to the gods or the universe or whatever there is that controls “the hands of fate”, as has been said thousands of times before. The hands of fate change your current situation. That is why it’s a wheel of fortune. It’s not a literal ‘fortune’, because we know fate can break or make us. The Wheel keeps our lives moving, and always changing. There is a lot of symbolism going on in this card and it can be rather overbearing at times when reading. The Wheel is in the clouds. The Wheel is part of divinity, not humanity. This is sensible, since sometimes fate isn’t always up to us. There is an angel, ox, lion, snake, eagle,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding love, I would say this is extremely interesting to find in your future position. Most likely, it will mean a change in your love life. Whatever it is, you’ll see a transformation occur to you. But, you do not know what kind of transformation the WOF is going to bestow you … or more like, what place the perpetually cycling wheel is going to end up on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;elements&quot;&gt;ELEMENTS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this reading, there is a fire card in the past position. As I explained in my last reading to you, Wands are very active, but this particular card, the Nine of Wands (9W), has a subtle nature to it. 
The next two cards are Empress in the present, and Wheel of Fortune in the future. Both are Major Arcana’s, but they have elements attached as well. I tend to associate Empress with air, since she is like Venus, and Venus in Western astrology is Libra (an air sign). However, she has an earthy feel to her, so she is a dual elemental card. The positives and negatives of each element play with each other. Earth is stubborn and grounded, but air lifts that austerity and allows it to free certain inhibitions. Air is always changing ways; sometimes can’t pick one thing over the other. Go east or west? But earth keeps air on a steady current.
The Empress has the best of both worlds because of these two polarizing yet complimentary elements.
WOF is divine rather than a physical elemental. The consensus among most Tarot readers is WOF invokes the fire element. However I personally think it’s difficult to see it as such, which is why I’ve made it a Divine Card. It is beyond and above any physical substance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s interesting because in your last reading we saw you received a 5W (Five of Wands) in the future position suggesting fire turning into the main elemental of your life … And so with this reading, we can see that future already occurring, it seems. It’s certainly a reinforcement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;relationship-between-all-three&quot;&gt;RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN ALL THREE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A) Past and Present&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This card signifies the amazing amount of stamina you have; that stamina of holding onto a love for the same person for so long. You still stand strong. You have some bruises to your body, mainly from the fact your love is unreciprocated, but it’s “just a scratch”. You can still stand up and latch onto the Wand you have. Nothing is stopping you from continuing on admiring the man you love so much. 
The 9W also means the rejection you faced when you asked him out, and found out he is already in a relationship. That might have wounded you, but it didn’t deter you from hoping. The Wand you hold onto is still there, keeping you up. The subtle fiery passion you have within your soul continues to flicker. However, you are guarded. You’ll be more careful around this man, now knowing he’s in a relationship. Every move can ruin the possibilities you could have with him. For now you are observing the setting from afar, and keeping a low guard to prevent any more wounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B) Present and Future&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t need something or someone else controlling your fate. If we looked at the WOF separately, it would be reasonable to say that you’d have to leave your life up to the strings that tug your destiny. But with the Empress on your side, you have the power to make your own outcome. The Empress is showing you have a lot more power than you think you do. Some things you might not be able to change, because the WOF is beyond human grasp and in its own personal realm, however changes or transformation that occur on the humans physical plane will permit you to grab and shake those changes to your fancy. You don’t need to take something you don’t like; you can manipulate it, as long as it resides on the human realm of possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;soulmate-analysis&quot;&gt;SOULMATE ANALYSIS:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this section, I will discuss the analysis of whether the man you have loved for so long, has some sort of soul mate connection with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, a big theory in modern spiritual thought is the idea that we all have more than one soul mate. Some soul mates are our teachers or family members, or people we spend a lot of time with. We tend to either break or make long lasting bonds with these soul mates. We meet with them to learn valuable lessons in our life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally don’t agree these people are our soul mates. There’s another factor we must consider here: the concept of a Twin Flame. So while many spiritual people think soul mates are people we learn lessons from, they have created a new idea to compensate for the concept of an eternal lover. Twin Flames are what we really mean to call our romantic soul mate… this phrase has replaced the soul mate term in our modern times. Twin Flames are eternal lovers that are ‘one’, but they are in separate bodies. Sometimes they never meet each other in life, but they are supposed to … at a certain time, usually when karmic ties have unbounded and they are ready to be with each other. It’s not always easy with Twin Flame though. There are a lot of things that try to break them apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the sake of simplicity, we will use the term soul mate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, onto the actual analysis of what the Tarot says. I drew an extra card, specifically asking if you had some sort of past connection with this man, because the initial spread gave no indication as to whether he was your soul mate or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/judgement.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Judgement was drawn&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is Yes. You did have a past connection with this man. You did well with listening to your inner voice – intuition -. 
The connection is showing itself right now, since you’ve known him for so long. Judgement deals a lot with karma in this case. When we have past connections with others, we have a shared relationship built on karma. The karma could be good or bad. That is revealed in time, through the dealings you have with the individual. You have known him for so long, retaining some sort of communication with him so there is a definite reason you are drawn to him. Judgement is saying through time, this relationship will reveal itself, blaringly loud. Just like how the divine figure is trumpeting it’s ‘announcement’ throughout the Earth, to all the fellow humans. It’ll be a coming for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the WOF is in the future position, the Tarot is saying a change is arriving, regarding your relationship with the man you love. How long it will take for this change depends. Generally when I do a past, present and future reading, the future tends to take more than half of a year to reveal itself (there are always exceptions). Not “occur” but reveals itself. Things are revealed to you, and you can either take that opportunity or flee from it. As well, every Tarot reading is a snapshot of the present moment. Yes, it may give insight into the future, but that possible future is dependent on the present you. If you take a different path (and if you can hear your intuition well, you’ll know), then the future will be entirely different from what you thought it would be. Keep that in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He has a girlfriend right now, so timing is everything. Fortunately, the Tarot is giving you hope. Not every single little thing will be left up for you to do. The WOF will help with the abstract, due to its divine nature. You just don’t know what area the Wheel will land on. If in the future, you’re dissatisfied with the place the Wheel landed on, remember the Empress has given you a one up. Don’t ever think you don’t have power. It’s clear to me you do have a lot of innate power, from seeing this spread and the past spread. You just need to discover and properly utilize it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To briefly sum up: A relationship is certainly a possibility. A definite yes or no is unclear, right now, because he is wrapped up in his own relationship. The Tarot says to retain the power of the Empress, cultivate the love, watch closely but don’t make any sudden moves because the WOF will guide you with that. Just like in your last reading you received 5W, telling you to be carefree. The same goes for this reading. Let the WOF do what it needs to do. And with the Judgement card that I drew, it could very well mean all that karmic energy that has been held will finally release into what needs to be done … and that is a closer relationship to this man. The relationship would most likely start out as a tighter bond as in friendship, but could easily move onto more ONLY if the WOF lands on the section of fate that permits it. But even if it doesn’t, don’t give up hope either, since you could have the power to wedge that Wheel just a smidgen to your favor. Just a small prick can change everything and cause the Wheel to change again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;closing&quot;&gt;Closing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do hope this has given you some insight into your relationship with the man you have been harboring a love towards. I was very glad to have the opportunity to provide this reading for you since love matters are something I enjoy most of all. Love is a fascinating phenomenon humans get to experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-April&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ACE</name><email>aceiotasirrah@gmail.com</email></author><category term="tarot reading" /><category term="email tarot reading" /><category term="my tarot reading example" /><category term="writing sample" /><summary type="html">This was a tarot reading I wrote for a customer back in October 9. It also contains valuable insights into the tarot and spirituality as a whole.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post: Standard</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/post%20formats/test/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post: Standard" /><published>2017-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/post%20formats/test</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/post%20formats/test/">&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Penguins&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ACE</name><email>aceiotasirrah@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Post Formats" /><category term="readability" /><category term="standard" /><summary type="html">Penguins</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Illustration: 2.5 x 10^6 ly</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/illustration/andromeda-galaxy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Illustration: 2.5 x 10^6 ly" /><published>2016-07-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-07-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/illustration/andromeda-galaxy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/illustration/andromeda-galaxy/">&lt;p&gt;The value is associated with astronomy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gallery/redandiota.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gallery/redandiota_flipped.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is another black and white image. It seems like I am trying to avoid colour images. Well, not with the last… (Variance Number 4).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, the good thing that I’ve noticed is that I am doing these black and white images a lot quicker. The linework still takes time, but the actual blacking in is taking less and less each picture. This one was an easy one though I had worked on it for several weeks, on and off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favourite part of the image? The galaxy in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Red and Iota, the leaders of the Rebel group, until Red (the guy with the long hair) goes on a mission somewhere else. Iota on the other hand, is not as charismatic, hardly, making for a bad leader. He is austere, deep in thought and generally not a great Andromedian to chat with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this picture I wanted to incorporate more design. Originally it wasn’t going to have the black borders nor the value, however I was itching to make more out of this piece. It looked boring without the value and borders. This now closes it and makes it polished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the original sketch. I had forgotten the galaxy was going to be titled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/risketch.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ACE</name><email>aceiotasirrah@gmail.com</email></author><category term="black and white" /><category term="design process" /><category term="illustration" /><category term="space opera" /><category term="iota" /><category term="red" /><category term="lineart" /><category term="how to draw black and white" /><category term="process" /><category term="composition" /><summary type="html">The value is associated with astronomy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Painting: Variance Number 4</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/painting/variance-no-4/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Painting: Variance Number 4" /><published>2016-07-14T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-07-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/painting/variance-no-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/painting/variance-no-4/">&lt;p&gt;Here’s variance number 4. I suppose I skipped number 3 too soon.
The International Accounting Concept midterm exam was due today. So I am turning this in as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/sigmanathumbnail.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not here not there, not where.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sigmana is the feature. This stemmed from a montage of sketches I wanted to do of Sigmana and Phirem. This one was a sketch I wanted to completely develop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/sigmanasketch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I retained the sketchy background, though reducing the opacity to 39%. It gives it a good edge, messy, gritty, rich. It’s too smooth without it. And I like the way the orange clashes with the red, though the red mixes with the weak blue carefully. The weak blue is on a different saturation level from the red, but the red pops within the confines of the blues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original size of the image is huge: &lt;strong&gt;4000 x 4800&lt;/strong&gt;. But here it’s down to 11% of its original size. Additionally a few adjustments to the originals curves allowing the light to be equal amongst the darks was done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there’s that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ACE</name><email>aceiotasirrah@gmail.com</email></author><category term="composition" /><category term="illustration" /><category term="sigmana" /><category term="space opera" /><category term="variance" /><category term="color design" /><category term="sketches" /><summary type="html">Here’s variance number 4. I suppose I skipped number 3 too soon.
The International Accounting Concept midterm exam was due today. So I am turning this in as well.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Illustration: Cruise Capt. Jessie</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/illustration/too-long/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Illustration: Cruise Capt. Jessie" /><published>2016-06-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-06-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/illustration/too-long</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/illustration/too-long/">&lt;p&gt;Just took too long for something so simple. There were a lot of mental ebbs and flows during the first half of June.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gallery/jessieticket_transparent.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is Cruise Captain Jessie (space opera character). Jessie, in a more caricature depiction, is in an earlier post titled 80s Retrospective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jessie is an Andromedian, and is a licensed Cruise Captain. She operates her own cruise line business with her own ship named Enlighters. Most people in my space opera world can teleport to wherever they want between MWG, Andromeda and Triangulum (as long as they teleport to the proper points of references that are accepted by the computer systems) but relaxing cruises throughout space is big business. People from all over it love it, and they can casually communicate with other species which is not often available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enlighters cruises between Milky Way and Andromeda. Usually, the ship follows its own unique course and it teleports to a set of progressed points in its journey, where it cruises for a certain amount of time, highlighting some celestial objects, then teleports to the next point to speed up; at the end, it retraces its path and ends up at the docking station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ship is massive and is almost like a planet in the nature that it has everything that can please the space tourists. It has to please tourists from alien and like cultures. Typically Enlighters cruise duration is one week. There are off seasons when the ship needs to be repaired or updated. Actually, Jessie’s ship is acting as an outdated model, but its internals have been updated. Passengers have always been charmed by Enlighters old world quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enough of talking about the ship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My idea with the picture was to make it like a photo you see in a magazine or brochure. The cruise pass is in that shape, just larger and with a glaring advertisement on the face. Cruise Captain Jessie is next to it. Her hat has always been based off of aviation but her suit is navy like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is her rough outfit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/june/roughcoloursjessie.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Realistic’ meaning her hair is not as light blue as it was in the cartoon like version in the linked article above. Generally, when I want to make something serious I make sure the colours aren’t over the top unless it truly is part of that character’s personality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, it’s another black and white picture to practice black and white. A coloured version wouldn’t be a bad idea, but I have to move on to other pictures that need to be done.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ACE</name><email>aceiotasirrah@gmail.com</email></author><category term="black and white" /><category term="design process" /><category term="illustration" /><category term="space opera" /><category term="jessie" /><category term="lineart" /><category term="how to draw black and white" /><category term="process" /><category term="composition" /><summary type="html">Just took too long for something so simple. There were a lot of mental ebbs and flows during the first half of June.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tutorial: Creating Definition with Black and White</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tutorial/creating-definition/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tutorial: Creating Definition with Black and White" /><published>2016-05-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-05-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tutorial/creating-definition</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tutorial/creating-definition/">&lt;p&gt;In commemoration of spending 8 hours and 25 mins total on all 5 of my final exams for this semester, I’m going to write a short entry on creating definition with black and white work, using my Mima fanart example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot; &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gallery/mima_full.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Mima&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gallery/mima_full.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mima&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;ZUN’S PC-98 Mima
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This picture I am working on is actually fan art. I hardly do fan art. The last time I did fan art was a while ago. The reason why I don’t draw fan art is because I don’t like devoting time to drawing another creator’s character(s). I rather spend that time working on creating my own stuff. It’s just not fun to draw someone else’s character(s), even though there are tons of character designs I really like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I like Mima a lot, and because ZUN doesn’t give the players much to work with (design wise), I wanted to do a Mima picture. Mima’s design isn’t built out since she was made in the beginning days of Touhou, so it’s a lot of fun to ‘redo’ a design, or ‘add on’ to an existing design. Adding your own flair to the character.
This illustration and design of Mima probably wouldn’t be popular with Touhou fan-fans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-create-depth&quot;&gt;How to create depth?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to discuss this with artistic terms. Creating work is a kinesthetic operation mixed with a visual bent, so there is no need to mix in terms art majors and teachers of art use. The best way for me to explain the operation of creating definition with black and white is to translate the raw practicality to raw words.
When making black and white works, you need to approach the art differently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask, “How can I create depth with just black and white?”
What techniques do you like to use when you draw, or paint? Use those in a practice work, but exclude the colour. For those that work in colour often, trapped is a good word for what one might feel when using limited palette, but black and white can be easier than using a limited colour palette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I start a black and white picture I keep it simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; Sketch
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; Sketch double over
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; Sketch triple over
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;4.&lt;/strong&gt; Sketch __ over until lineart can be drawn without erasing or fixing lineart errors
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;5.&lt;/strong&gt; Thicken lineart if needed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But also, don’t trap yourself. Make as many layers as you want to ensure you will have freedom in your lineart. I never do lineart on one layer. For me, it’s a very claustrophobic feeling. When the hair layer is separate from the face, and I don’t like the hair layer, then I can delete the hair or erase the hair without worrying that it’ll impact other layers. This freedom helps break down any tense feelings. Tense feelings can destroy the process of creating a work. In order to create a work you have to flow with it. No rigidity in yourself. This principle is relevant to any of the creative processes, whether it’s making a sculpture, or creating a piece of music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/may/mimaroughs.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;avoid-unnecessary-lines-in-black-and-white-lineart&quot;&gt;Avoid unnecessary lines in black and white lineart&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When making lineart for a black and white picture, I advise not putting any unnecessary lines. Unnecessary lines will bother the freedom of adding the definition. When you have unnecessary lines, you might unconsciously or consciously adhere to the form of those lines. You want an absolutely clean and clear white unobstructed by these unnecessary lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of unnecessary lines to the base line art, are lines on a person’s face, such as when they smile, or wrinkles… things like that. Hair strands within the hair, clothing folds. You shouldn’t put these into the base lineart. Severely minimize them to the best of your ability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;free-form&quot;&gt;Free Form&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, in my Mima picture, I do not put hair lines into her hair. It took me awhile to not insert unnecessary lines in my work. 
At first, it’s hard to not put these unnecessary lines in, and it’s hard to work ‘free form’ (no lines except the outer lines for the line art that displays the base of the work). And of course, some of you might have easily surpassed this or never had a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can’t work ‘free form’, then create the unnecessary lines on a separate layer. Lower the opacity of that layer and work with it. Eventually, you should train yourself to do free form. 
The process of free form requires:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; Practice
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; Visual knowledge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn how to do a person’s face without adding the unnecessary lines, study faces and practice without adding the lines. After a few bouts of practice it gets easier. Your work will look a lot better too. Unnecessary lines look awful most of the time.
We have just discussed one step to creating definition.
However, the next step will be the ‘anti-freeform’. It requires making lines to create some definition, though not quite like the unnecessary lines in the above paragraphs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;anti-freeform&quot;&gt;Anti-freeform&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lines you make in this step are needed in order for definition to come forth. Think of this step as the colouring process after making your sketch, or base. Except, you are colouring with black. It just can’t be called colouring, technically, because it’s using black and white. It also can’t technically be called inking because we are assuming this is being done digitally (but if not, then it certainly is inking). Still, you can cal it whatever you’d like. I just think of it as the next process in completing the work.
The anti-freeform lines are best explained in visuals. The face and hands are a good start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/may/hand1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remember:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; the purpose of avoiding these lines in the base lineart is because the picture is not set in stone. Things need to flow in a logical manner. Adding lines in the base lineart will impact the liquidity of how well you can manipulate the last process (adding the definition by ‘colouring’, ‘inking’ (whatever you want to call it)). Add step by step. Make your steps but adhere to the steps. That is the secret to finishing the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/may/face1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice I filled in the eyes after I was done with the base lineart. Does such a minute detail matter? To answer that question, read the above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few lines in the base lineart. They are minimal and were added in confidence. Furthermore, I knew exactly what to do with those lines. I accented their appearance. While you must be minimal in your unnecessary lines, remember that not all lines are unnecessary, especially if you are confident and know what you’re doing. 
To illustrate unnecessary lines better, here is the comparison with the character’s hair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/may/hairzoom.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A zoom in a certain area I deem an ‘unnecessary line’. It impacted my ability to complete the hair successfully. It should have been drawn after the base lineart; it doesn’t match with the rest of the lineart. Some harmony has been lost in the base lineart because of just one error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, why is this part of the hair not considered an unnecessary line?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/may/hair3zoom.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because this hair is flowing out from the main hair piece. So, it’s alright in comparison to the previous example.
These examples will help you understand what I mean by unnecessary lines. Ultimately, it’s your judgement. If you have a good eye for what causes a disturbance in your picture, you will know, but only if you have a good eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;concluding-remarks&quot;&gt;Concluding remarks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, try these steps out and then manipulate them to the way you work, because one should never limit their selves to a certain process or style. When you learn to manipulate techniques, you will create your own style, visually and mentally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; Remove unnecessary lines/ do not incorporate them into line art
&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; Line art must be against crisp clean white background
&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; Apply anti-freeform to create the actual depth 
&lt;strong&gt;4.&lt;/strong&gt; Use your judgement&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ACE</name><email>aceiotasirrah@gmail.com</email></author><category term="black and white" /><category term="design process" /><category term="illustration" /><category term="tutorial" /><category term="lineart" /><category term="how to draw black and white" /><category term="creating artistic definition" /><category term="process" /><category term="composition" /><summary type="html">In commemoration of spending 8 hours and 25 mins total on all 5 of my final exams for this semester, I’m going to write a short entry on creating definition with black and white work, using my Mima fanart example.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Painting: Variance Number 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/design%20process/composition/variance/color%20design/painting/variance-no-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Painting: Variance Number 2" /><published>2016-04-29T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-04-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/design%20process/composition/variance/color%20design/painting/variance-no-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/design%20process/composition/variance/color%20design/painting/variance-no-2/">&lt;p&gt;This is Variance Number Second. Actually, the first one was posted already, however I didn’t conjure the name to describe the style at the time. Cerulean Twins is Variance Number One.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dark-colours&quot;&gt;Dark Colours&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot; &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gallery/m.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Original dark version&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gallery/m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;dark version&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Dark portrait
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished this back in March; it’s only till now I feel like posting it. It’s a dark picture, isn’t it? I think it’s one of my mistakes. It looks like a filter has been applied, but really, those are the colours I picked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I have been writing this entry, I fixed it with curves. This is what it’s supposed to look like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gallery/m_curves.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to be gentle with the curves. The painting needs to keep its warmness, but avoid being too saturated. The stark red and purplish pinks can cause that if you’re not careful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the colour tables. The first one is the original, and the second is the newest one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/colourtable_original.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/colourtable_new.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change the picture to index mode and you can view the big picture – the colour table. The second table is more consistent… enough vibrancy to contrast with the duller colours. The first table doesn’t have many vibrant colours flowing with the dull. A little depressing.
Colour table comparisons are a great analysis tool; helps discover problems with images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like both versions but it’s easier to see the details in the lighter picture. Additionally, most people would find the first picture simply too dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Did you darken the painting?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“No …”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Better to avoid those situations by improving.
As for the image itself, I wanted to pick colours that matched the personality of the person. Most of the colours are muted, but there are the splashes and that’s what count when it comes to personality. Those vibrant lights come forth, minimizing the fortified wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus funky:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/spectrum_mac.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-tip&quot;&gt;A tip:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t paint when the laptop light is below 100% brightness or less than an optimal amount.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ACE</name><email>aceiotasirrah@gmail.com</email></author><category term="process" /><category term="composition" /><category term="illustration" /><category term="portrait" /><category term="sketches" /><category term="variance" /><category term="color design" /><category term="painting" /><summary type="html">This is Variance Number Second. Actually, the first one was posted already, however I didn’t conjure the name to describe the style at the time. Cerulean Twins is Variance Number One.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sketches: Concept Work</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/design%20process/composition/variance/color%20design/sketches/concept/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sketches: Concept Work" /><published>2016-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/design%20process/composition/variance/color%20design/sketches/concept</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/design%20process/composition/variance/color%20design/sketches/concept/">&lt;p&gt;After two weeks I have time to post some stuff I’m working on. The main work is my newest ‘more creative’ work, after the great practice Cerulean Twins provided. 
Before I post it, here are some other things of interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sigmanas-original-outfit&quot;&gt;Sigmana’s Original Outfit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/sigmana1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concept of Sigmana in formal wear. It’s a very 70s-80s design. Probably all my designs are heavily inspired by the 80s, but what can I do? The theme, if noticeable on first observance, are primary colours. I’ve always liked Sigmana’s primary colour outfit. The golden skirt is metallic, and half open. Not part of S’s dress; it’s simply added, making S’s regular dress formal. That’s all there is to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/sigmanaback0.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my story, S isn’t particularly keen of the formal additions; it’s quite trite. Her skirt of the dress is my favourite part… it’s big and fluffy, reminiscent of the 1950s. In the future, they don’t wear crinolines though, so activity is not hampered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/iotagang1.png&quot; title=&quot;Iota and the gang sketch&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/iotagang1.png&quot; alt=&quot;sketch&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/iotagang2.png&quot; title=&quot;Painting in my variance style&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/iotagang2.png&quot; alt=&quot;painting&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next is Iota and the gang. I still don’t know what to do with this picture. It might be colour, it might be black and white. I’m leaning towards colour, because I’d like to do one colour picture showcasing Iota’s gang. Anyways, I like Iota’s face here. For several years I had been trying to draw him realistic, but my skills weren’t able to translate what was in my mind. Now, this right here, is what I think he’d look like in real life.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ACE</name><email>aceiotasirrah@gmail.com</email></author><category term="process" /><category term="composition" /><category term="illustration" /><category term="portrait" /><category term="sigmana" /><category term="phirem" /><category term="sketches" /><category term="art reference" /><category term="variance" /><category term="color design" /><category term="sketches" /><category term="space opera" /><summary type="html">After two weeks I have time to post some stuff I’m working on. The main work is my newest ‘more creative’ work, after the great practice Cerulean Twins provided. 
Before I post it, here are some other things of interest.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Painting: Cerulean Twins Completed</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/design%20process/composition/variance/illustration/joint-venture/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Painting: Cerulean Twins Completed" /><published>2016-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/design%20process/composition/variance/illustration/joint-venture</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/design%20process/composition/variance/illustration/joint-venture/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve finished this more ‘ creative ‘ piece, first detailed in Cerulean Sketches. View that post to see the compositions. I like how it turned out. I didn’t want it to be cut and dry, as in, extremely clean and careful. So I let myself go, which I am getting better at. As an illustrator, it’s good to veer away from the usual things, because what I’ve learned from doing this piece, I will use for future pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dislike-for-mistakes&quot;&gt;Dislike for Mistakes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was younger, I hated any kind of mistake in my work. A small line here, and then a wrong mark there … it drove me. But look at how unclean this stuff is. There’s smudges of different colours in the background; it’s not a clear cerulean. I tried to mimic a natural painted look. It was easy to let go of what my younger self would think, “small mistakes”, in order to retain an organic appearance. The organic appearance is noted with a ‘flow’ that can be detected when analyzing the piece. Indeed, the shapes are angular – sharp and pointed, harbouring a stiff aesthetic – but the overall picture flows inward to expel a coordinated visual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;character-insight&quot;&gt;Character Insight&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The characters are Sigmana (long hair), and the twin, Phirem (short hair). I seem to always draw young Sigmana with its face lifted up, and Phirem’s face lowered … but that’s due to how strong their personality impacts my representation of them. Sigmana is a curious creature and being the prototype for its twin, Phirem, is in a constant mode of wonder. Phirem is quite the opposite – there’s no ‘wonder’ of the universe grounding it, but more of desire for the universe wondering at Phirem. That could be why I unconsciously drew Phirem’s hands the way I did, the form of “creating power”, although it looks odd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;progress&quot;&gt;Progress&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, the angular lines are becoming clearer in my work. Liberal use of triangular, hard shapes. And then there are still flowing shapes, for example, the garments the two twins wear, as well as their hair. I just wanted for this to be a shape picture; more a practice of my techniques and skill. How far I can go with being uncomfortable. Not one ounce of discomfort arose while working on this piece. So, I would say this was a successful maneuver. 
There are not many work in process pictures, simply because this work is not an ‘accurate’ work; it didn’t call for many precise revisions to achieve the final state. It was an ‘inaccurate’ work, meaning, the work is the way it is, liberally worked on using more of the mind and flows of the hand rather than including a logical set of steps to complete it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ACE</name><email>aceiotasirrah@gmail.com</email></author><category term="process" /><category term="composition" /><category term="illustration" /><category term="marie" /><category term="jessie" /><category term="sigmana" /><category term="phirem" /><category term="space opera" /><category term="art reference" /><category term="variance" /><category term="color design" /><summary type="html">I’ve finished this more ‘ creative ‘ piece, first detailed in Cerulean Sketches. View that post to see the compositions. I like how it turned out. I didn’t want it to be cut and dry, as in, extremely clean and careful. So I let myself go, which I am getting better at. As an illustrator, it’s good to veer away from the usual things, because what I’ve learned from doing this piece, I will use for future pieces.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Illustration: LeCoile and Marie</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/design%20process/composition/illustration/black%20and%20white/lecoile-marie/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Illustration: LeCoile and Marie" /><published>2016-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/design%20process/composition/illustration/black%20and%20white/lecoile-marie</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/design%20process/composition/illustration/black%20and%20white/lecoile-marie/">&lt;p&gt;More of my characters from my sci-fi story. This time it’s teenage (about 19 years old) LeCoile and Marie. LeCoile is a fairly effeminate male, but does it matter in the year 3700 AD~? And Marie has been on this page, in the 80s retrospective (link). She’s a mechanical engineer; has a sort of anarchist personality, very chaotic neutral I’d say. Her mother is a famous scientist part of the “Inverts” science group, made up of 4 other genius scientists put together by the world leaders. Because of this, Marie didn’t see her mother a lot as a child, so she spent time living next door to LeCoile’s family (who also, are scientists, but local). At her teenage years, she hasn’t seen her mother since she was 8~ yrs. And the whereabouts of her father are unknown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They live next to a massive ocean, but it can get cold during the fall and winter!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;third &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/4_lineart.png&quot; title=&quot;Original sketch&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/4_lineart.png&quot; alt=&quot;original&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/5_lineart.png&quot; title=&quot;Revising Marie's face...&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/5_lineart.png&quot; alt=&quot;revising&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/1_lineart.png&quot; title=&quot;Base lineart&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/1_lineart.png&quot; alt=&quot;base lineart&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Steps in the process.
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed working on the gnarly tree the most in this picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/2_lineart.png&quot; title=&quot;Filling it in&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/2_lineart.png&quot; alt=&quot;filling&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/3_lineart.png&quot; title=&quot;Zoom on tree&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/3_lineart.png&quot; alt=&quot;zoom&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The other half of the process.
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, I was at a lost where to start, but I had to get over the mental block and go wild. I’d like to go wilder, but one has to be careful where to place the lines and shading as well (which is where the initial mental block arose). You can’t just place any line anywhere. And if you already made lines, in the line art base, it might not look right when you shade the picture. It’s better to have a fairly blank slate to work with, and simply transfer the image from your mind into the picture. Most importantly, the mental block has to be removed. You can’t think to yourself how the picture will look every second you place a line. Do it first and then look at it 5 minutes later. Erase if you don’t like it (hopefully not, because then 5 minutes are lost). I try to erase the least possible but sometimes I really don’t like the way I did a shading so I redo it all over again. A lot of time is lost doing this, but it gives my mind a ‘drug’ to calm down. I’m working on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This picture has been in my ‘file cabinet’ for several months. Most of the picture was completed in November. Once again, the mental block worked against me in the completing it, but I fought through this month and finally finished it thoroughly afterwards. The picture was first created Tuesday, October 27, 2015 … and finished at the end of January this month.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ACE</name><email>aceiotasirrah@gmail.com</email></author><category term="process" /><category term="composition" /><category term="illustration" /><category term="marie" /><category term="lecoile" /><category term="space opera" /><category term="black and white" /><summary type="html">More of my characters from my sci-fi story. This time it’s teenage (about 19 years old) LeCoile and Marie. LeCoile is a fairly effeminate male, but does it matter in the year 3700 AD~? And Marie has been on this page, in the 80s retrospective (link). She’s a mechanical engineer; has a sort of anarchist personality, very chaotic neutral I’d say. Her mother is a famous scientist part of the “Inverts” science group, made up of 4 other genius scientists put together by the world leaders. Because of this, Marie didn’t see her mother a lot as a child, so she spent time living next door to LeCoile’s family (who also, are scientists, but local). At her teenage years, she hasn’t seen her mother since she was 8~ yrs. And the whereabouts of her father are unknown.</summary></entry></feed>
