<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title>Stuff Full of Stuff</title>
	<link href="http://iotaace.github.io/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="http://stuffostuff.com/blog"/>
	<updated>2017-01-11T02:38:04+00:00</updated>
	<id>http://iotaace.github.io/blog/</id>
	<author>
		<name>test</name>
		<email>mailto:</email>
	</author>

	
		<entry>
			<title></title>
			<link href="http://stuffostuff.com/2016-01-20-80sretro/"/>
			<updated>2017-01-11T02:38:04+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://stuffostuff.com//2016-01-20-80sretro</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In December, I had the bright idea of making a New Year’s picture. I’ve always wanted to do a picture of characters in 80s ski clothes. With my increasingly funky cel shading, I thought the 80s theme would fit well. The characters are from my sci-fi creation, Marie and Jessie. Jessie’s the one with the light blue hair; she’s an Andromedian. Marie’s the dark blue haired girl who has a penchant for mechanical work, and lives on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initial ski outfit inspiration was from some years ago, when I saw Takei Masaki’s artbook, Sotsugyou (Graduation). The illustrations were character designs of each girl you could get with in the PC98 game, Sotsugyou. Each girl had an illustration of her skiing, with funky outfits.  I love Takei Masaki’s hard, angular lines and shading. His peak was in the 90s, and following through into the 2000s; unfortunately, his modern artwork turned softer and much more vulgar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot; &quot;&gt;
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;These are the compositions for the picture.
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew I was going to give it a light blue background. It would also have a ‘present’ wrapped look, with diagonal blocks showcasing various text on the upper left and lower right sides of the pictures. Though, I wasn’t sure how I was going to pull that off, until much later in the process of the picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this was going to be an 80s retrospective picture, I looked up a lot of 80s ski images on google. I had to get an idea of how skis work, as well as what sort of position the body took. It had to be a dynamic image. Picking out the colours was the most exciting part. I wanted to use colours from an old computer palette, so I chose the MSX2. I did break away a little by selecting my own colours, so the image isn’t a true MSX2 colour palette. But this was a great exercise to get used to restriction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These were the original colours I thought of before using the palette … a placeholder to mark up some ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new colours. Most of the picture utilized the MSX2 palette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marie is a tomboy character while Jessie is a little more ‘feminine’ (but very bossy since she operates a touring spaceship hotel). I wasn’t positive a light pink ski suit would match Marie too well, but with her dynamic pose of jumping in the air in contrast to Jessie’s demure ‘gliding’, adds a boyish flair that neutralizes the pink costume. Both Marie and Jessie’s costume colours utilize the MSX2 palette. Marie’s symbol that I like to draw her with are stars, so I made sure to add that to her suit. Not only that, but the bright yellow with aqua gives a very 80s design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jessie’s costume colours are my favourite. The red and blue aren’t neon or saturated, but match the quality of 80s to early 90s ski costumes. More of the mountaineering, ruddy look rather than a fun costume. It’s legitimate; a real skier who wanted to appear slightly blazing fashionable would wear it. Her purple gloves are flamboyant and carefully match the red and blue theme. Avoidance of garish colour combos was a must; tasteful combinations were considered instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was stuck a little bit concerning the background, but what got me rolling was a snowflake brush I found after searching google. It seems once you find one thing, the rest comes naturally. ‘Welcome to 2016’ was given a neon glow, and rounded font common during the 70s and 80s (but less common after the 80s). The font does have a modern appearance; while this is a retrospective picture, it is also welcoming the transition to the New Year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The picture is like a thank you card, or a forgotten post card. I wasn’t born in the 1980s but the 80s mean a lot to me. Most of the things I like stem from the 80s and early 90s. This is one of my praises to that time period&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Post: Standard</title>
			<link href="http://stuffostuff.com/post%20formats/test/"/>
			<updated>2017-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://stuffostuff.com//post%20formats/test</id>
			<content type="html">
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Penguins&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
			<link href="http://stuffostuff.com/jekyll/okay/"/>
			<updated>2016-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://stuffostuff.com//jekyll/okay</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	

</feed>
