<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title>Stuff Full of Stuff</title>
	<link href="http://iotaace.github.io/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="http://stuffostuff.com/blog"/>
	<updated>2017-02-05T00:27:26+00:00</updated>
	<id>http://iotaace.github.io/blog/</id>
	<author>
		<name>test</name>
		<email>mailto:</email>
	</author>

	
		<entry>
			<title>Painting: Variance Number 6</title>
			<link href="http://stuffostuff.com/painting/variance-no-6/"/>
			<updated>2017-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://stuffostuff.com//painting/variance-no-6</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I set this variance as the header for the splash page of my portfolio. This is a bold and bizarre piece that I had sketched out back in August. But it was only in January this year that I completed it, thanks to time permitting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot; &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gallery/radface3.png&quot; title=&quot;Variance Number 6&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gallery/radface3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common theme I like to draw are the twins, Sigmana and Phirem. I like to draw them because I can make them look disheveled, bizarre, unconventional. I’m tired of seeing artists draw characters that look like picture perfect models, and from the other side of the spectrum, uninteresting “shapes”. One of my influences for making the delicate creatures is Nagano Mamoru illustrations of his characters. Particularly, his Fatima’s look haunting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I tried to pick print safe colours, but, because I had this image on the backburner for months, I didn’t care when I picked it up again a few weeks ago. Nevertheless, I kept the palette at a minimum and chose vibrant, almost jarring colours. When I do a variance painting, I like to choose colours that may not work next to each other. Sometimes colours we think are disharmonious together, can be used to support or emphasize on another colour. I played it safe with this piece, though. Sigmana’s dull blue hair is a great contrast to the hot pink background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is another large image (6500 x 3300). A larger view is accessible through the gallery, in the portfolio section.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Painting: Twins</title>
			<link href="http://stuffostuff.com/painting/twins/"/>
			<updated>2017-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://stuffostuff.com//painting/twins</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Again, this is Sigmana and Phirem (the twins). I’ve drawn them a lot, but the next pictures planned have nothing to do with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot; &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gallery/thetwins3.png&quot; title=&quot;Twins&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gallery/thetwins3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked on this throughout December, and finished it in the beginning of January. It wasn’t a difficult piece; originally I was going to make it lineart, but after seeing how my painting looked without the lines, I decided to make it look realistic. I particularly like how Sigmana’s face turned out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since they are both artificially created, they aren’t supposed to look organic, though Phirem has quite an expressive personality. Sigmana is the prototype, or the ‘not as good as it could be’ type, so it’s going to look expressionless (Sigmana is well aware of its existence, however).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their skin colour is a sickly blue, with some signs of ‘life’ around their eyes (pink).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;phirem&quot;&gt;Phirem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I struggled a lot with making Phirem’s face. I looked at references of mischevous children and fortunately, that helped. Still, to get a certain emotion out of its face was a challenge, and I am pleased with the result. Here are some sketches of what the twins looked like before. When I have difficulty, I will sketch many, many times until I get it right, or I do a study in which I practice a reference. This way, I am learning how to apply it to my own piece, as well as learning how to draw [a certain thing].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;third &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/feb2017/floating.png&quot; title=&quot;Floating head&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/feb2017/floating.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/feb2017/sketch_t.png&quot; title=&quot;Original sketches (sort of)&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/feb2017/sketch_t.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/feb2017/sketch_t2.png&quot; title=&quot;Pretty bad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/feb2017/sketch_t2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Written Image: Content</title>
			<link href="http://stuffostuff.com/written%20image/content/"/>
			<updated>2016-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://stuffostuff.com//written%20image/content</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;this piece is enourmous: &lt;strong&gt;4748 x 3500&lt;/strong&gt;. best viewed in full screen; please view it in the gallery as well!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stuffostuff.com/assets/images/gallery/sunflowerfall.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stuffostuff.com/assets/images/gallery/sunflowerfall.png&quot; alt=&quot;foo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;setting-the-tone&quot;&gt;Setting the tone&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a very simple piece. Another written image, similar to the Jellyfish. One can say it’s the grownup version of the standard child’s drawing of a hill, house, sun, tree and stick figure, due to the horizontal composition. Much of the inspiration came from a dedicated video of Tuxedomoon’s piece “Lowlands Tone Poem”, and a house I would walk by as I went to the grocery store. The house looked standard of the area where my university is located; shabby, but it had a unique charm to it: many sunflowers right out front. I thought, ‘this house is not American’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;his-emotions&quot;&gt;His emotions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His appearance here amongst the minimal setting fleshes his personality completely. He isn’t depressed, and he isn’t a sad fellow. He isn’t happy either. He just is what he is. I think that’s the best way to live life, not to have so many ups and downs. Going through life as an active observer and aware of your environment, you tend to be content, forgiving of other people, and generally an easy going person. These types of individuals are not wishy-washy; they aren’t ecstatic, nor wild or morose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;background-on-the-creation&quot;&gt;Background on the creation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the creation of the image: the image is huge - 4748 x 3500 pixels. Not a good idea to draw this large with black and white work. It took a very long time and at some points, the work was exceedingly tedious and painful. Drawing each individual sunflower was a pretty bad experience. I spent a few weeks mulling over how I would plan out the sunflowers and I had difficulty drawing them at first (after some practice, I figured out my way of drawing these bright flowers). I was frustrated, and kept flip flopping between not including the flowers in the picture. I wagered the picture simply is not the same without the sunflowers – after all, it is my primary inspiration for the piece. After the initial line work was complete, the drawing went smoothly. To make the effect of the body of the sunflower, I simply laid over a noise layer. There’s no way I’d do each individual dot for each sunflower. Pure masochism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was going to be a street lamp, but maybe it would crowd the picture. On a second thought, perhaps I should have added it. There’s also no blue shed either, though I imagine he’s coming close to it. The priority was on the sunflowers and sky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, I too walk with an umbrella and briefcase.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Written Image: Jellyfish</title>
			<link href="http://stuffostuff.com/written%20image/jellyfish/"/>
			<updated>2016-09-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://stuffostuff.com//written%20image/jellyfish</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-jellyfish&quot;&gt;2 Jellyfish&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gallery/jellyfish_duplicate_3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-rest&quot;&gt;The rest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I wrote about jellyfish. I’m not going to say this is a poem – I won’t claim I can write poetry. Instead, I wrote an image on jellyfish. Images are different from poems … I think my goal was to create something that moves, rather than crafting with words. By this word ‘written image’, I mean the qualitative characteristics of what an image, which is a visual representation of a thing, provides. Think of the term ‘written image’ as something more technical and abstract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-a-written-image-in-my-terms&quot;&gt;What is a written image (in my terms)?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, words weren’t enough, so I decided to take writing an image literally: drawing an image (now, I use the term ‘image’ with the basic connotation: visual representation). That’s what makes a written image complete. A poem can have an image attached, but was the poem originally intended to have an image? If it wasn’t intended to have an image then it’s certainly a poem. If an image was in mind and then included, then there is a written image. Take note that the words are also a part of the drawing. It’s not in a random space on the page, but blending with the jellyfish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is what a written image is, summed up in a basic manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an addition to this post, my portfolio would not be complete without the actual drawing. Here’s the jellyfish without the written image. I am pleased with the line work. I drew the jellyfish in a quick manner; about two hours total. I kept the shading and bw work at a minimum because that would obscure the very delicate line work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/september/jellyfish_lineart.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Painting: Variance Number 5</title>
			<link href="http://stuffostuff.com/painting/variance-no-5/"/>
			<updated>2016-09-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://stuffostuff.com//painting/variance-no-5</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gallery/wolfe1_copy_3_lineart_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each time I look at this picture I get the sense of – dryness –. Certain amount of ugliness. There’s enough vibrancy to ensure this picture will gather the attention of those that enjoy neon colour schemes, but it is subdued by the dull background – pale mauve, gray periwinkle and a midnight blue: light enough to share the same space with the mauve and periwinkle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is also my first definite picture to incorporate only CMYK values. They were selected from the Pantone +CMYK library. It worked pretty well. This was the palette I worked with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/september/palette.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only colour I didn’t use was the light green. 
I proofed the image, and only the green in the man’s cloak dulls a tad; the green was mixed too much with the blue while painting, so the green, which is greenish-blue, does not properly come out when switched to CMYK. The rest of the colours keep consistent.
The initial concept came from a sketch I drew in an old sketch book of mine, back in 2014. I probably sketched it in one of my art classes and I was going to eventually plan it out as an image but I never did. The character is Wolfe, a shape shifter. Two years later, and here is a much nicer rendition of the original. I do not have this sketch book with me currently so no scan of the original is available. 
A black and white creation of the image might be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/wolfe1_lineart.png&quot; caption=&quot;Wolfe lineart&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Illustration: Brom</title>
			<link href="http://stuffostuff.com/illustration/brom/"/>
			<updated>2016-08-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://stuffostuff.com//illustration/brom</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m trying to come up with a comfortable, conventional colouring style that involves some sort of line art. I’ve spent too much time with black and white so I am lacking. With this piece, I decided to use my Variance style, twisting it to make it less abstract. More importantly, this is a concept character design (that I redid three times) and was great colouring practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;space-detective-brom&quot;&gt;Space Detective Brom&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gallery/brom2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is Brom, a concept art of a character. He’s a space detective and has a cyborg eye. Well I didn’t want the eye to look so mechanical and average. So it’s simply blue, though his eye changes colours depending on what wavelength he needs to hone in on. Blue is for visible light. He looks pretty regular as far as detectives go, besides his hair. I realized too late that his hair bears a little resemblance to Professor Oak… Ahh, well I did want Brom to have a ‘cyberpunk’ hair style. Sleek hair is popular in fashion today, but not popular with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overlay-manipulation&quot;&gt;Overlay manipulation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another good practice was overlay manipulation to get some above standard effects. It was boring with just the colouring. I like the texture I gave to the coat, as well as some dirt to the shoes.
There were a lot of revisions with this picture. Check them out here (this was the cause for the unbelievable long time it took to finish his design):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/brom_1.png&quot; title=&quot;A different version of Brom&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/brom_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;different version&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/brom_2.png&quot; title=&quot;Brom sketch&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/brom_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;brom sketch&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Illustration: 2.5 x 10^6 ly</title>
			<link href="http://stuffostuff.com/illustration/andromeda-galaxy/"/>
			<updated>2016-07-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://stuffostuff.com//illustration/andromeda-galaxy</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The value is associated with astronomy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gallery/redandiota.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gallery/redandiota_flipped.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is another black and white image. It seems like I am trying to avoid colour images. Well, not with the last… (Variance Number 4).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, the good thing that I’ve noticed is that I am doing these black and white images a lot quicker. The linework still takes time, but the actual blacking in is taking less and less each picture. This one was an easy one though I had worked on it for several weeks, on and off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favourite part of the image? The galaxy in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Red and Iota, the leaders of the Rebel group, until Red (the guy with the long hair) goes on a mission somewhere else. Iota on the other hand, is not as charismatic, hardly, making for a bad leader. He is austere, deep in thought and generally not a great Andromedian to chat with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this picture I wanted to incorporate more design. Originally it wasn’t going to have the black borders nor the value, however I was itching to make more out of this piece. It looked boring without the value and borders. This now closes it and makes it polished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the original sketch. I had forgotten the galaxy was going to be titled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/risketch.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Painting: Variance Number 4</title>
			<link href="http://stuffostuff.com/painting/variance-no-4/"/>
			<updated>2016-07-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://stuffostuff.com//painting/variance-no-4</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here’s variance number 4. I suppose I skipped number 3 too soon.
The International Accounting Concept midterm exam was due today. So I am turning this in as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/sigmanathumbnail.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not here not there, not where.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sigmana is the feature. This stemmed from a montage of sketches I wanted to do of Sigmana and Phirem. This one was a sketch I wanted to completely develop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/sigmanasketch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I retained the sketchy background, though reducing the opacity to 39%. It gives it a good edge, messy, gritty, rich. It’s too smooth without it. And I like the way the orange clashes with the red, though the red mixes with the weak blue carefully. The weak blue is on a different saturation level from the red, but the red pops within the confines of the blues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original size of the image is huge: &lt;strong&gt;4000 x 4800&lt;/strong&gt;. But here it’s down to 11% of its original size. Additionally a few adjustments to the originals curves allowing the light to be equal amongst the darks was done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there’s that.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Illustration: Cruise Capt. Jessie</title>
			<link href="http://stuffostuff.com/illustration/too-long/"/>
			<updated>2016-06-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://stuffostuff.com//illustration/too-long</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just took too long for something so simple. There were a lot of mental ebbs and flows during the first half of June.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gallery/jessieticket_transparent.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is Cruise Captain Jessie (space opera character). Jessie, in a more caricature depiction, is in an earlier post titled 80s Retrospective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jessie is an Andromedian, and is a licensed Cruise Captain. She operates her own cruise line business with her own ship named Enlighters. Most people in my space opera world can teleport to wherever they want between MWG, Andromeda and Triangulum (as long as they teleport to the proper points of references that are accepted by the computer systems) but relaxing cruises throughout space is big business. People from all over it love it, and they can casually communicate with other species which is not often available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enlighters cruises between Milky Way and Andromeda. Usually, the ship follows its own unique course and it teleports to a set of progressed points in its journey, where it cruises for a certain amount of time, highlighting some celestial objects, then teleports to the next point to speed up; at the end, it retraces its path and ends up at the docking station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ship is massive and is almost like a planet in the nature that it has everything that can please the space tourists. It has to please tourists from alien and like cultures. Typically Enlighters cruise duration is one week. There are off seasons when the ship needs to be repaired or updated. Actually, Jessie’s ship is acting as an outdated model, but its internals have been updated. Passengers have always been charmed by Enlighters old world quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enough of talking about the ship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My idea with the picture was to make it like a photo you see in a magazine or brochure. The cruise pass is in that shape, just larger and with a glaring advertisement on the face. Cruise Captain Jessie is next to it. Her hat has always been based off of aviation but her suit is navy like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is her rough outfit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/june/roughcoloursjessie.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Realistic’ meaning her hair is not as light blue as it was in the cartoon like version in the linked article above. Generally, when I want to make something serious I make sure the colours aren’t over the top unless it truly is part of that character’s personality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, it’s another black and white picture to practice black and white. A coloured version wouldn’t be a bad idea, but I have to move on to other pictures that need to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Tutorial: Creating Definition with Black and White</title>
			<link href="http://stuffostuff.com/tutorial/creating-definition/"/>
			<updated>2016-05-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://stuffostuff.com//tutorial/creating-definition</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In commemoration of spending 8 hours and 25 mins total on all 5 of my final exams for this semester, I’m going to write a short entry on creating definition with black and white work, using my Mima fanart example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot; &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gallery/mima_full.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Mima&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gallery/mima_full.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mima&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;ZUN’S PC-98 Mima
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This picture I am working on is actually fan art. I hardly do fan art. The last time I did fan art was a while ago. The reason why I don’t draw fan art is because I don’t like devoting time to drawing another creator’s character(s). I rather spend that time working on creating my own stuff. It’s just not fun to draw someone else’s character(s), even though there are tons of character designs I really like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I like Mima a lot, and because ZUN doesn’t give the players much to work with (design wise), I wanted to do a Mima picture. Mima’s design isn’t built out since she was made in the beginning days of Touhou, so it’s a lot of fun to ‘redo’ a design, or ‘add on’ to an existing design. Adding your own flair to the character.
This illustration and design of Mima probably wouldn’t be popular with Touhou fan-fans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-create-depth&quot;&gt;How to create depth?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to discuss this with artistic terms. Creating work is a kinesthetic operation mixed with a visual bent, so there is no need to mix in terms art majors and teachers of art use. The best way for me to explain the operation of creating definition with black and white is to translate the raw practicality to raw words.
When making black and white works, you need to approach the art differently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask, “How can I create depth with just black and white?”
What techniques do you like to use when you draw, or paint? Use those in a practice work, but exclude the colour. For those that work in colour often, trapped is a good word for what one might feel when using limited palette, but black and white can be easier than using a limited colour palette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I start a black and white picture I keep it simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; Sketch
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; Sketch double over
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; Sketch triple over
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;4.&lt;/strong&gt; Sketch __ over until lineart can be drawn without erasing or fixing lineart errors
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;5.&lt;/strong&gt; Thicken lineart if needed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But also, don’t trap yourself. Make as many layers as you want to ensure you will have freedom in your lineart. I never do lineart on one layer. For me, it’s a very claustrophobic feeling. When the hair layer is separate from the face, and I don’t like the hair layer, then I can delete the hair or erase the hair without worrying that it’ll impact other layers. This freedom helps break down any tense feelings. Tense feelings can destroy the process of creating a work. In order to create a work you have to flow with it. No rigidity in yourself. This principle is relevant to any of the creative processes, whether it’s making a sculpture, or creating a piece of music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/may/mimaroughs.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;avoid-unnecessary-lines-in-black-and-white-lineart&quot;&gt;Avoid unnecessary lines in black and white lineart&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When making lineart for a black and white picture, I advise not putting any unnecessary lines. Unnecessary lines will bother the freedom of adding the definition. When you have unnecessary lines, you might unconsciously or consciously adhere to the form of those lines. You want an absolutely clean and clear white unobstructed by these unnecessary lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of unnecessary lines to the base line art, are lines on a person’s face, such as when they smile, or wrinkles… things like that. Hair strands within the hair, clothing folds. You shouldn’t put these into the base lineart. Severely minimize them to the best of your ability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;free-form&quot;&gt;Free Form&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, in my Mima picture, I do not put hair lines into her hair. It took me awhile to not insert unnecessary lines in my work. 
At first, it’s hard to not put these unnecessary lines in, and it’s hard to work ‘free form’ (no lines except the outer lines for the line art that displays the base of the work). And of course, some of you might have easily surpassed this or never had a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can’t work ‘free form’, then create the unnecessary lines on a separate layer. Lower the opacity of that layer and work with it. Eventually, you should train yourself to do free form. 
The process of free form requires:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; Practice
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; Visual knowledge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn how to do a person’s face without adding the unnecessary lines, study faces and practice without adding the lines. After a few bouts of practice it gets easier. Your work will look a lot better too. Unnecessary lines look awful most of the time.
We have just discussed one step to creating definition.
However, the next step will be the ‘anti-freeform’. It requires making lines to create some definition, though not quite like the unnecessary lines in the above paragraphs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;anti-freeform&quot;&gt;Anti-freeform&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lines you make in this step are needed in order for definition to come forth. Think of this step as the colouring process after making your sketch, or base. Except, you are colouring with black. It just can’t be called colouring, technically, because it’s using black and white. It also can’t technically be called inking because we are assuming this is being done digitally (but if not, then it certainly is inking). Still, you can cal it whatever you’d like. I just think of it as the next process in completing the work.
The anti-freeform lines are best explained in visuals. The face and hands are a good start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/may/hand1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remember:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; the purpose of avoiding these lines in the base lineart is because the picture is not set in stone. Things need to flow in a logical manner. Adding lines in the base lineart will impact the liquidity of how well you can manipulate the last process (adding the definition by ‘colouring’, ‘inking’ (whatever you want to call it)). Add step by step. Make your steps but adhere to the steps. That is the secret to finishing the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/may/face1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice I filled in the eyes after I was done with the base lineart. Does such a minute detail matter? To answer that question, read the above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few lines in the base lineart. They are minimal and were added in confidence. Furthermore, I knew exactly what to do with those lines. I accented their appearance. While you must be minimal in your unnecessary lines, remember that not all lines are unnecessary, especially if you are confident and know what you’re doing. 
To illustrate unnecessary lines better, here is the comparison with the character’s hair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/may/hairzoom.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A zoom in a certain area I deem an ‘unnecessary line’. It impacted my ability to complete the hair successfully. It should have been drawn after the base lineart; it doesn’t match with the rest of the lineart. Some harmony has been lost in the base lineart because of just one error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, why is this part of the hair not considered an unnecessary line?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/may/hair3zoom.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because this hair is flowing out from the main hair piece. So, it’s alright in comparison to the previous example.
These examples will help you understand what I mean by unnecessary lines. Ultimately, it’s your judgement. If you have a good eye for what causes a disturbance in your picture, you will know, but only if you have a good eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;concluding-remarks&quot;&gt;Concluding remarks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, try these steps out and then manipulate them to the way you work, because one should never limit their selves to a certain process or style. When you learn to manipulate techniques, you will create your own style, visually and mentally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; Remove unnecessary lines/ do not incorporate them into line art
&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; Line art must be against crisp clean white background
&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; Apply anti-freeform to create the actual depth 
&lt;strong&gt;4.&lt;/strong&gt; Use your judgement&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Painting: Variance Number 2</title>
			<link href="http://stuffostuff.com/painting/variance-no-2/"/>
			<updated>2016-04-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
			<id>http://stuffostuff.com//painting/variance-no-2</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is Variance Number Second. Actually, the first one was posted already, however I didn’t conjure the name to describe the style at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cerulean Twins is Variance Number One.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dark-colours&quot;&gt;Dark Colours&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot; &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gallery/m.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Original dark version&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gallery/m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;dark version&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Dark portrait
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished this back in March; it’s only till now I feel like posting it. It’s a dark picture, isn’t it? I think it’s one of my mistakes. It looks like a filter has been applied, but really, those are the colours I picked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I have been writing this entry, I fixed it with curves. This is what it’s supposed to look like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gallery/m_curves.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to be gentle with the curves. The painting needs to keep its warmness, but avoid being too saturated. The stark red and purplish pinks can cause that if you’re not careful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the colour tables. The first one is the original, and the second is the newest one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/colourtable_original.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/colourtable_new.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change the picture to index mode and you can view the big picture – the colour table. The second table is more consistent… enough vibrancy to contrast with the duller colours. The first table doesn’t have many vibrant colours flowing with the dull. A little depressing.
Colour table comparisons are a great analysis tool; helps discover problems with images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like both versions but it’s easier to see the details in the lighter picture. Additionally, most people would find the first picture simply too dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Did you darken the painting?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“No …”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Better to avoid those situations by improving.
As for the image itself, I wanted to pick colours that matched the personality of the person. Most of the colours are muted, but there are the splashes and that’s what count when it comes to personality. Those vibrant lights come forth, minimizing the fortified wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus funky:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/spectrum_mac.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-tip&quot;&gt;A tip:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t paint when the laptop light is below 100% brightness or less than an optimal amount.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Sketches: Concept Work</title>
			<link href="http://stuffostuff.com/sketches/concept/"/>
			<updated>2016-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://stuffostuff.com//sketches/concept</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After two weeks I have time to post some stuff I’m working on. The main work is my newest ‘more creative’ work, after the great practice Cerulean Twins provided. 
Before I post it, here are some other things of interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sigmanas-original-outfit&quot;&gt;Sigmana’s Original Outfit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/sigmana1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concept of Sigmana in formal wear. It’s a very 70s-80s design. Probably all my designs are heavily inspired by the 80s, but what can I do? The theme, if noticeable on first observance, are primary colours. I’ve always liked Sigmana’s primary colour outfit. The golden skirt is metallic, and half open. Not part of S’s dress; it’s simply added, making S’s regular dress formal. That’s all there is to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/sigmanaback0.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my story, S isn’t particularly keen of the formal additions; it’s quite trite. Her skirt of the dress is my favourite part… it’s big and fluffy, reminiscent of the 1950s. In the future, they don’t wear crinolines though, so activity is not hampered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/iotagang1.png&quot; title=&quot;Iota and the gang sketch&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/iotagang1.png&quot; alt=&quot;sketch&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/iotagang2.png&quot; title=&quot;Painting in my variance style&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/iotagang2.png&quot; alt=&quot;painting&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next is Iota and the gang. I still don’t know what to do with this picture. It might be colour, it might be black and white. I’m leaning towards colour, because I’d like to do one colour picture showcasing Iota’s gang. Anyways, I like Iota’s face here. For several years I had been trying to draw him realistic, but my skills weren’t able to translate what was in my mind. Now, this right here, is what I think he’d look like in real life.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Painting: Cerulean Twins Completed</title>
			<link href="http://stuffostuff.com/painting/joint-venture/"/>
			<updated>2016-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://stuffostuff.com//painting/joint-venture</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve finished this more ‘ creative ‘ piece, first detailed in Cerulean Sketches. View that post to see the compositions. I like how it turned out. I didn’t want it to be cut and dry, as in, extremely clean and careful. So I let myself go, which I am getting better at. As an illustrator, it’s good to veer away from the usual things, because what I’ve learned from doing this piece, I will use for future pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dislike-for-mistakes&quot;&gt;Dislike for Mistakes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was younger, I hated any kind of mistake in my work. A small line here, and then a wrong mark there … it drove me. But look at how unclean this stuff is. There’s smudges of different colours in the background; it’s not a clear cerulean. I tried to mimic a natural painted look. It was easy to let go of what my younger self would think, “small mistakes”, in order to retain an organic appearance. The organic appearance is noted with a ‘flow’ that can be detected when analyzing the piece. Indeed, the shapes are angular – sharp and pointed, harbouring a stiff aesthetic – but the overall picture flows inward to expel a coordinated visual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;character-insight&quot;&gt;Character Insight&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The characters are Sigmana (long hair), and the twin, Phirem (short hair). I seem to always draw young Sigmana with its face lifted up, and Phirem’s face lowered … but that’s due to how strong their personality impacts my representation of them. Sigmana is a curious creature and being the prototype for its twin, Phirem, is in a constant mode of wonder. Phirem is quite the opposite – there’s no ‘wonder’ of the universe grounding it, but more of desire for the universe wondering at Phirem. That could be why I unconsciously drew Phirem’s hands the way I did, the form of “creating power”, although it looks odd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;progress&quot;&gt;Progress&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, the angular lines are becoming clearer in my work. Liberal use of triangular, hard shapes. And then there are still flowing shapes, for example, the garments the two twins wear, as well as their hair. I just wanted for this to be a shape picture; more a practice of my techniques and skill. How far I can go with being uncomfortable. Not one ounce of discomfort arose while working on this piece. So, I would say this was a successful maneuver. 
There are not many work in process pictures, simply because this work is not an ‘accurate’ work; it didn’t call for many precise revisions to achieve the final state. It was an ‘inaccurate’ work, meaning, the work is the way it is, liberally worked on using more of the mind and flows of the hand rather than including a logical set of steps to complete it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Illustration: LeCoile and Marie</title>
			<link href="http://stuffostuff.com/illustration/lecoile-marie/"/>
			<updated>2016-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://stuffostuff.com//illustration/lecoile-marie</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;More of my characters from my sci-fi story. This time it’s teenage (about 19 years old) LeCoile and Marie. LeCoile is a fairly effeminate male, but does it matter in the year 3700 AD~? And Marie has been on this page, in the 80s retrospective (link). She’s a mechanical engineer; has a sort of anarchist personality, very chaotic neutral I’d say. Her mother is a famous scientist part of the “Inverts” science group, made up of 4 other genius scientists put together by the world leaders. Because of this, Marie didn’t see her mother a lot as a child, so she spent time living next door to LeCoile’s family (who also, are scientists, but local). At her teenage years, she hasn’t seen her mother since she was 8~ yrs. And the whereabouts of her father are unknown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They live next to a massive ocean, but it can get cold during the fall and winter!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;third &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/4_lineart.png&quot; title=&quot;Original sketch&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/4_lineart.png&quot; alt=&quot;original&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/5_lineart.png&quot; title=&quot;Revising Marie's face...&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/5_lineart.png&quot; alt=&quot;revising&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/1_lineart.png&quot; title=&quot;Base lineart&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/1_lineart.png&quot; alt=&quot;base lineart&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Steps in the process.
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed working on the gnarly tree the most in this picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/2_lineart.png&quot; title=&quot;Filling it in&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/2_lineart.png&quot; alt=&quot;filling&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/3_lineart.png&quot; title=&quot;Zoom on tree&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/3_lineart.png&quot; alt=&quot;zoom&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The other half of the process.
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, I was at a lost where to start, but I had to get over the mental block and go wild. I’d like to go wilder, but one has to be careful where to place the lines and shading as well (which is where the initial mental block arose). You can’t just place any line anywhere. And if you already made lines, in the line art base, it might not look right when you shade the picture. It’s better to have a fairly blank slate to work with, and simply transfer the image from your mind into the picture. Most importantly, the mental block has to be removed. You can’t think to yourself how the picture will look every second you place a line. Do it first and then look at it 5 minutes later. Erase if you don’t like it (hopefully not, because then 5 minutes are lost). I try to erase the least possible but sometimes I really don’t like the way I did a shading so I redo it all over again. A lot of time is lost doing this, but it gives my mind a ‘drug’ to calm down. I’m working on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This picture has been in my ‘file cabinet’ for several months. Most of the picture was completed in November. Once again, the mental block worked against me in the completing it, but I fought through this month and finally finished it thoroughly afterwards. The picture was first created Tuesday, October 27, 2015 … and finished at the end of January this month.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Sketches: Cerulean Sketches</title>
			<link href="http://stuffostuff.com/sketches/cerulean-sketches/"/>
			<updated>2016-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://stuffostuff.com//sketches/cerulean-sketches</id>
			<content type="html">
&lt;figure class=&quot;third &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/cerulean.png&quot; title=&quot;Cerulean twins: work in progress&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/cerulean.png&quot; alt=&quot;wip&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/cerulean_3.png&quot; title=&quot;Original sketch&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/cerulean_3.png&quot; alt=&quot;original sketch&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/cerulean_2.png&quot; title=&quot;Lineart for painting&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/cerulean_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;lineart&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The latest work. Compositions.
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always manage to find time to work on my stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have for the longest time (many, many years), wanted to make a more ‘artistic’ piece, where the main colour was a blaring cerulean. A lot of times I let colour guide the entire process of the picture, and it can really change the way the picture was originally set out to be. The picture is the colour and it is entirely based on the colour. Without the colour, there’s no statement and no character, or story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cerulean piece in question: Sigmana (long hair) and Phirem (short hair), right when they are out of their artificial intelligence machines. Their mother is watching them from beyond with her unwavering glare. They are aliens, so they aren’t supposed to be beautiful. I want the eyes and lips and overall face to look weary for all of them. The mother has bulging eyes and long paper-thin eyelashes. I want to make the mother look as stoic but uncanny as possible. 
I thought I was going to do Sigmana and Phirem as line art, but then I experimented a little bit and figured doing an orange and blue paint of their silhouettes is best. Darker shadows of their bodies and garment will be the blue of the background. The mother will be the ‘prime’ target – bolder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;another-work-in-progress&quot;&gt;Another work in progress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/nerve.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a work in progress which stirred from an idea I had two years ago. I had a dream and after I woke up; I sketched the picture. The character was in a weird cavern that was full of muscles, cells, nervous system … hair separated from the head. So I used my character Phirem. Phirem is an alien, a creation, so it’s impossible Phirem has the inners of a human or any kind of organic being but inorganic material circuiting through.
Right now it’s just a line art of the body but as you can see by this sketch:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/nerve_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;after the body base will be completed, a layer will be drawn on top consisting of sinewy threads.  The body base is made so it will be easier … I need to remind myself not to make the line art ‘too’ perfect. Ctrl-z, draw, ctrl-z … repeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More on these as I continue to work through them.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Illustration: 80s Retrospective</title>
			<link href="http://stuffostuff.com/illustration/eightiesretro/"/>
			<updated>2016-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
			<id>http://stuffostuff.com//illustration/eightiesretro</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In December, I had the bright idea of making a New Year’s picture. I’ve always wanted to do a picture of characters in 80s ski clothes. With my increasingly funky cel shading, I thought the 80s theme would fit well. The characters are from my sci-fi creation, Marie and Jessie. Jessie’s the one with the light blue hair; she’s an Andromedian. Marie’s the dark blue haired girl who has a penchant for mechanical work, and lives on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initial ski outfit inspiration was from some years ago, when I saw Takei Masaki’s artbook, Sotsugyou (Graduation). The illustrations were character designs of each girl you could get with in the PC98 game, Sotsugyou. Each girl had an illustration of her skiing, with funky outfits.  I love Takei Masaki’s hard, angular lines and shading. His peak was in the 90s, and following through into the 2000s; unfortunately, his modern artwork turned softer and much more vulgar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half &quot;&gt;
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/sketch1.png&quot; title=&quot;Original sketch&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/sketch1.png&quot; alt=&quot;original sketch&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
    
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/sketch2.png&quot; title=&quot;Revised sketch&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/content/sketch2.png&quot; alt=&quot;revised sketch&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    
  
  
    &lt;figcaption&gt;These are the compositions for the picture.
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew I was going to give it a light blue background. It would also have a ‘present’ wrapped look, with diagonal blocks showcasing various text on the upper left and lower right sides of the pictures. Though, I wasn’t sure how I was going to pull that off, until much later in the process of the picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this was going to be an 80s retrospective picture, I looked up a lot of 80s ski images on google. I had to get an idea of how skis work, as well as what sort of position the body took. It had to be a dynamic image. Picking out the colours was the most exciting part. I wanted to use colours from an old computer palette, so I chose the MSX2. I did break away a little by selecting my own colours, so the image isn’t a true MSX2 colour palette. But this was a great exercise to get used to restriction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These were the original colours I thought of before using the palette … a placeholder to mark up some ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/sketch3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new colours. Most of the picture utilized the MSX2 palette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/sketch4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marie is a tomboy character while Jessie is a little more ‘feminine’ (but very bossy since she operates a touring spaceship hotel). I wasn’t positive a light pink ski suit would match Marie too well, but with her dynamic pose of jumping in the air in contrast to Jessie’s demure ‘gliding’, adds a boyish flair that neutralizes the pink costume. Both Marie and Jessie’s costume colours utilize the MSX2 palette. Marie’s symbol that I like to draw her with are stars, so I made sure to add that to her suit. Not only that, but the bright yellow with aqua gives a very 80s design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jessie’s costume colours are my favourite. The red and blue aren’t neon or saturated, but match the quality of 80s to early 90s ski costumes. More of the mountaineering, ruddy look rather than a fun costume. It’s legitimate; a real skier who wanted to appear slightly blazing fashionable would wear it. Her purple gloves are flamboyant and carefully match the red and blue theme. Avoidance of garish colour combos was a must; tasteful combinations were considered instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was stuck a little bit concerning the background, but what got me rolling was a snowflake brush I found after searching google. It seems once you find one thing, the rest comes naturally. ‘Welcome to 2016’ was given a neon glow, and rounded font common during the 70s and 80s (but less common after the 80s). The font does have a modern appearance; while this is a retrospective picture, it is also welcoming the transition to the New Year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The picture is like a thank you card, or a forgotten post card. I wasn’t born in the 1980s but the 80s mean a lot to me. Most of the things I like stem from the 80s and early 90s. This is one of my praises to that time period.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
		</entry>
	

</feed>
